hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation playlist now
continuing with our obstacles topic so
we are going to look at the next
obstacle which is called the testing
methods now this particular obstacle
contains a multi- select test box which
contains a lot of different testing
methods which are supported by tosa and
we need to select these testing methods
from this particular list box okay so we
need to select a functional testing and
then we need to select GUI
testing right and then we need to select
end to end and exploratory right and
then if all of them are selected then
this particular obstacle will be solved
now this this you need to do through
automation right and to achieve this we
need to uh use two different concepts in
TOA so let's see what are these now to
make it uh easier I have already scanned
this particular module so I have
selected these two controls which is the
select drop-down or multibox and then
the item itself right so you don't need
to select all the items because they
would be similar in nature right only
the names are changing but all the
properties will remain same for all the
items so we don't need to select uh all
the items separately that's not the
ideal way of doing this uh we can just
select one of the items and then as I
said we need to use two different
concepts here
right so uh the first concept is uh we
need to change the cardinality okay so
the cardinality by default is is set to
0 to one which means uh you can only use
this particular uh module attribute once
right now here what we need to do is we
need to uh click on this module
attribute number of times uh for four
different testing methods I need to
click or I need to use this module
attribute four times right so the
cardinality uh helps you to basically um
use the module attribute multiple times
okay so if you change the cardinality if
you increase the range then you can use
it multiple times so what uh we can do
here is we can just change the
cardinality from 0 to 1 to 0 to n so I
can use this particular module attribute
n number of times
okay the second thing which we have to
do is we have to add a configuration
parameter so right click on the item and
then select create configuration
parameter now here we need to use
something called explicit
name right now we have discussed about
this earlier so what is explicit name
and we need to set the value to true so
what this will do is uh it will help me
to rename this item in my test case
itself okay so if I rename it in the
module attribute then it will reflect it
in the test case or test step but since
I have to use uh different testing
method names right like this so I want
to change the item name uh in each test
step okay so these are the two changes
which you need to do at a module
attribute level so you need to change
the cardinality and then you need to add
a configuration parameter which is
explicit name set to True okay now uh
let's build a test case out of this so
let's go to our obstacles and here uh we
are going to create a new test case I am
going to use this particular obstacle as
the test case
name okay and then uh we can just drag
the module right here okay so as you can
see uh in the test step we have got the
select drop-down and then we have got
the item okay
now uh as I said we need to use this
particular item number of times right so
what we will do is uh we are going to
rename this item okay to different
testing
methods and then you will see that once
you do that okay another item is already
there so I can use this multiple times
and this is due to the cardinality
property right so since we have
increased it to n number of times this
will keep on adding this particular item
as many times as you want okay uh so the
action mode will by default set to input
which means it is going to uh select or
click on that particular item okay uh
and now let's go ahead and add all the
remaining ones so we need end to end
testing okay so we also need to mention
testing here otherwise it will not
select it
and then end to end
testing right and then uh the GUI
testing and finally uh we will add the
explor
testing
okay and uh it can select all these
module attributes based on these names
and this is due to the explicit name
okay so both the concepts are being used
here and you can understand why we are
trying to use this okay so this is all
we have to do here so it will select
that particular list box and then it
will uh select all the items
individually uh together and it will
complete the rle okay so if I go ahead
and execute this now
okay so as you can see it selected all
the items in the background and it was
able to complete this particular uh
ridle right so as you can see it
selected all the different testing
methods uh in the multi- select list box
okay so couple of Concepts which was
covered uh in this particular obstacle
which was how you can select multiple
items in a list box
then um how you can use cardinality and
also explicit name for a module
attribute that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video